Bella Nicholson

♀ Amsterdam, Netherlands

% bellanich.github.io

in bella-nicholson

O bellanich

American

Resourceful Machine Learning Engineer with 3+ years of experience in a diverse set of organizations, ranging from tech startups and scaleups to an establish tech company. A life-long learner with a passion for optimizing ML models for realworld applications on resource-constrained devices. Excited about the intersection between engineering and AI research.

EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer

Brenntag

Mov 2023 - Present

Amsterdam, Netherlands

At the world's leading chemical distributor, I deployed and maintained ML products across 70+ countries. Thus far, I've:

- Migrated a virtual AI assistant (earning €30+ million in annual revenue) to a more cost-effective and secure AWS platform
- Developed a real-time notification system to monitor critical ML jobs and model metrics, improving system visibility
- Standardized quality controls across 15+ ML project components through the creation of a CLI package prototype

(Junior) AI Consultant

Deloitte Consulting

m Sept 2021 - Oct 2023

Amsterdam, Netherlands

As a contracted ML engineer, I optimized and implemented ML solutions for diverse clients, delivering:

- Increased system robustness of a Dutch e-classified ads platform's "For You" page, introduced MLOps best practices
- · Launched a self-paced, ML-focused coding training website to standardize and improve code quality across Deloitte NL
- · Centralized large-scale model storage, experiment tracking across various environments for a German steel conglomerate

Research Thesis Intern

Crunchr

math display="block"> Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

♀ Amsterdam, Netherlands

At a people analytics platform, I conducted graph-based representation learning research for the development of ML products:

- · Built a proof of concept, one-off representation learning process to encode relational database entity information
- Demonstrated approach validity by applying deep neural networks to downstream classification tasks on process outputs

Computer Vision Intern

Cubelizer

m June 2017 - July 2017

Madrid, Spain

As part of a Google-backed edge computer vision startup, I improved customer detection 12% in retail space optimization:

- Developed a video stream-based object detection method in compliance with EU privacy regulations
- · Applied image processing and classical machine learning techniques to low-resolution images

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning Engineering for Production (MLOps) Specialization

DeepLearning.Al

Curriculum

Sept 2022

Certificate

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Artificial Intelligence

University of Amsterdam

🗎 Sept 2018 - Dec 2020

- Amsterdam, Netherlands
- Courses on AI, including Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, and Reinforcement Learning
- Thesis on "Interpretable Representation Learning for Relational Data" in collaboration with Crunchr
- Cum laude (8.0/10.0)

Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Engineering

The College of New Jersey

Sept 2014 - May 2018

♀ Ewing, New Jersey, USA

- Met national engineering standards by passing the Fundamentals of Engineering Other Disciplines Exam
- Magna cum laude (3.8/4.0)

PROJECTS

Pocket Multi-Modal Foundation Model

- Deployed a custom embedded, vision-text foundation model across various iOS devices (laptop, phone, tablet)
- · Extended an existing large language model hardwareoptimization framework to quantize a new multi-modal model
- Documented results and process in a 4-part blog post series

Python Machine Learning Template

- Automated a comprehensive Python ML project setup process with a project template and 3 simple bash commands
- Enabled streamlined project creation with pre-built tests, an automated build process, and auto-generated documentation

SKILLS

Programming languages & tooling

Python, Git (2016-present), Bash (2018-present), Terraform (2023-present), SQL (2019-present), Docker (2022-present)

MLOps platforms

Amazon Web Services (2021-present), Google Cloud Platform (2022-present), Databricks (2022-present), Azure DevOps Platform (2021-2022)

ML frameworks

PyTorch (2018-present), PySpark (2022-present), FastAPI (2021-present), Tensorflow (2021-2022), Keras (2022)

Languages







Spanish

German

Russian